Thongo lam vuma, Lam vuma, Lam vuma, lam vuma. (Improvising) (Music ends) (Applause) Thandiswa Mazwai: Hello everybody. Thank you so much for having us here. My name is Thandiswa Mazwai. I am a wild woman, a rebel singer, a conduit. My music is about memory and struggling between oppresion and freedom. After over 20 years in South Africa we find ourselves as the black masses still suffering and fighting for our freedom and humanity. This first song was called "Iyeza" which means "medicine." Medicine for our madness, medicine for our rage. This song we're doing now is called "Zabalaza," and it means "rebel." I'd like to dedicate this to the valiant student movement in South Africa who came up with the #FeesMustFall. (Applause) Rhodes Must Fall. But more importantly, the new vigor that has been brought into the feminist movement so patriarchy must fall.
Thongo lam vuma Lam vuma, Thongo lam vuma, Lam vuma, lam vuma, (Improvisación) (Fin de la música) (Aplausos) Thandiswa Mazwai: Hola a todos. Gracias por la invitación. Me llamo Thandiswa Mazwai. Soy una mujer salvaje, cantante rebelde, una intermediaria. Mi música es sobre la memoria y la lucha entre la opresión y la libertad. En Sudáfrica, después de 20 años, nosotros, la inmensa la población negra, aún seguimos sufriendo y luchando por nuestra libertad y humanidad. La primera canción fue "Iyeza", que significa "medicina". Medicina para nuestra locura, medicina para nuestra ira. La canción que interpretaremos ahora se llama "Zabalaza", que significa "rebeldía". Quisiera dedicarla al valiente movimiento estudiantil de Sudáfrica que protestó contra el alza de colegiaturas (Aplausos) y la remoción de la estatua de Rhodes. Pero lo más importante es la nueva fuerza que cobró el movimiento feminista. Por eso, abajo el patriarcado.
(Applause) (Music) Gogo bek' umthwalo Kunin' uhlupheka? Little ghetto child Ungazibulali sana Oh ... If you take my hand, I'll show you
(Aplausos) (Música) Gogo bek' umthwalo Kunin' uhlupheka? Niñito del gueto Ungazibulali sana Oh... Si tomas mi mano, te mostraré
how to be free. Ayifanelang' ub' iyenzeka lento Emzini kabawo kunge kudala Sizozabalaza. Zabalaza, zabalaza. Zabalaza. Sizozabalaza. Zabalaza, zabalaza. Zabalaza. (Vocalizing) (Improvising) It's my people in Soweto, my people in Mozambique, my people in Senegal. These are my people in the ghettos. Zabalaza, zabalaza. Zabalaza. (Music ends) (Applause) (Cheering) Thank you very much. (Applause)
cómo ser libre. Ayifanelang' ub' iyenzeka lento Emzini kabawo kunge kudala Sizozabalaza. Zabalaza, zabalaza. Zabalaza. Sizozabalaza. Zabalaza, zabalaza. Zabalaza. (Vocalización) (Improvisación) Es mi gente de Soweto, mi gente de Mozambique, mi gente de Senegal. Esta es mi gente de los guetos. Zabalaza, zabalaza. Zabalaza. (Fin de la música) (Aplausos) (Ovación) Muchas gracias. (Aplausos)